okay so uh so this lecture is about uh
development and Robotics or development
and AI so uh the basic idea is what can
we learn about how to train robots from
what we know about how children grow up
that's the spirit and this okay this
slide is just always to remind you
but
uh uh this is the slide I want to
actually start with uh this is a quote
from Alan turing's 1950 paper I mean
this is the paper which uh which is like
the title is can machines think and it
proposed the so-called Turing test but
he has this beautiful line instead of
trying to produce a program to stimulate
the simulate the adult mind why not
rather try to produce one which
simulates the Childs If This Were then
subjected to an appropriate course of
Education one would obtain the adult
brain so Turing in 1950 had this idea
that the way to get to an artificial
intelligence is to start with the brain
of a baby so this is kind of like your
genetic capability basic genetic
capability is like the prior that you
build it and then after that you subject
the child to some course of
instruction and uh and then when the
child becomes an adult you've got your
AI
okay and uh now Turing was writing this
in
1950 and uh at that time actually what
we knew about Child Development was
rather limited there had been some
people who had some psychologists who
had studied the problem I mean the most
famous names are p and botski
WR them
down and this is a he was a Swiss
scientist and then
botski and this guy was in the Soviet
Union so if you are curious about the
early history of Child Development read
P or botski P emphasized the development
of of children through various stages of
capabilities voty emphasized the social
nature of learning uh how we learn from
the environment with peers and parents
and caregivers and so forth okay but we
know now a lot more details about how
children acquire their perceptual
capabilities their motor capabilities
and how they learn about the world and
uh there's so much to say here I mean I
I have a book here called uh
developmental robotics which is all
about how uh you know this interplay
between what we know from Child
Development and we can try to use for
Robotics and there are even conferences
on this there's a conference called icdl
which is uh International Conference on
development and learning which is on
this theme okay so so this area is uh
existed for like about 25 years people
have had this idea that let's try to uh
you know build robots in the same way
that children
learn uh the devil is of course in the
details I mean you can have this high
level idea but how do you operationalize
it so uh with a child I think if you
look at the figure you see some of the
stuff on the left which is this this
girl is in the crib and maybe she's
playing with various things and she's
tapping at various objects and so forth
so what's what's the kind of signal that
she will be getting
she'll take some object she'll put it
into her mouth so then there is the
tactile signal from the mouth there is
obviously the various joints joint
angles the proprioceptive information
there's Vision there is audition because
when you hit some object on something
you have a sound so it's a very
multimodal input and the child is
playing now uh on the uh in the course
of this so it's all self-directed
now there is this last stage when the
child goes to the zoo and the mom says
oh that's a zebra but that is like this
little tiny slaver of supervised
learning most of the learning is
essentially self-directed by the child I
wouldn't call it just unsupervised
learning I mean you can use the term
self-supervised learning because part of
it is
actually reinforcement learning as well
because the child is performing actions
and then observing the consequences of
that but the reinforcement learning or
learning to act in the world is in fact
more subtle than that because the child
is often not driven by very specific
goals but just goals to explore and play
and and and this is uh something we have
been trying to uh capture in Ai and
Robotics and not had very good luck like
the notion of what's called intrinsic
motivation
intrinsic
motivation and uh there's another
related term which is
curiosity so the child is interacting
with the world to learn more about the
world and build models so the way to
think of I think the right way to think
about it is as in my previous talk which
is that uh we require lots of models of
the world and the child's play is aimed
at building models of the world so when
the child is sitting in the crib and she
takes the the the the the bottle that
the mom has just given her and then the
child throws that bottle you should
think of it as an experiment to learn
about gravity right I mean parents of
course get very annoyed when the child
does all these things but the child is
really doing all these experiments to to
to build models of the
world okay uh there's a good
philosophical statement here which I
want to uh uh do this paper I think will
be on your reading this Smith and gas
because it's kind of a summary of the of
the big findings from this child
development literature I mean this
literature is huge I mean up here in
fact in this building on the in on the
psychology floor we have colleagues here
we have five or six colleagues who who
devoted their research carriers to
understanding how uh you know the the
process of Child Development so so they
have you know thousands of papers and
books and I cannot possibly do justice
in one hour so I'm going to give you a
projection of some of this to to
robotics uh but uh there is uh in this
paper which says uh uh embodied
cognition six lessons from babies so
there's one point which is this
embodiment hypothesis is the idea that
intelligence emerges in the interaction
of an agent with an environment and as a
result of sensory motor activity and
then they have abstracted out six six
points six
lessons so uh and what I'm going to do
is I'm going to give you examples of how
you can take these principles which come
from like this uh this paper written by
psychologist and how you can
operationalize them and get value out of
them in robotics I thought that
initially I planned this lecture as
giving you a review of the literature
from developmental psychology and I
think that's going to be overwhelming
and just too much so I'll really tried
to do it in from the point of view of uh
some examples of how it's been useful in
robotics so multi be multimodal uh so I
already gave you something about that
right so Vision touch appropr option Etc
be incremental so uh we do not learn you
know we don't have like oh there are
like 17 different skills Each of which
you will learn end to end separately
that's not how it works you acquire some
skills then on top of that you build the
next set of skills on top of that you
build the next set of skills and so
forth uh be physical all of these
require interacting with the physical
world exploration uh so it's this is
like explore in the same sense as in uh
explore exploit in the reinforcement
learning World social here means
learning from others and then finally
language so I'll give you some examples
of this but I'm going to start with uh
one one or two case studies which for me
were very influential meaning that I I
mean you
know there's one of these classic
debates that has occurred in AI for the
last 70 years there are some people who
care about looking at natural
intelligence and biology and psychology
and there other people who don't care
and those people stand up and they
usually always give this argument okay
you you want to airplanes don't fly like
birds therefore I do not care to know
about Birds go away I don't want to
learn anything about psychology or
neuros cells I mean I've heard this
argument like 177,000 times okay so uh
and maybe one some of you are exactly
from that school of thought sorry I
don't care I I believe in this and I I
I'm going to give you examples of what I
have learned and how it has benefited my
group's research in robotics so here was
one example which was like uh in
Locomotion so in Locomotion the standard
belief is that animals have Gates Right
and here's a picture of gates and in
fact I in my very first or second
lecture I I told you about walking and
running as two gates that humans
have so uh so uh and this has been
guiding the people in robotics forever
so starting from like Mark R bir's work
and including some of the learning work
that it starts by pre-programming a gate
so gate would be like the pattern of
footfalls so you program that in and
then you you start after to that you or
you build your controller based on that
pre-programmed notion of
gates okay and then
uh what I was doing was I was reading
some of this literature from the
psychologist and in particular there's a
psychologist called Karen Adolf she is
at New York University who she studies
how children learn to walk I mean she
studies many things but how children
learn to walk is a big thing and uh the
difference between how she studied
children learning to walk and other
other people who done this is she tried
to study it and as natural ass setting
as possible so she gives these kids who
come into the lab lots of room so that
they can walk in a much more free way
and get a sense of how they actually
learn as opposed to in a very very
constrainted setting and so she has a
whole bunch of these findings which uh
you should read about I think we'll put
one of those papers on the reading list
for example children fall a lot okay so
this is good because this tells you that
maybe RL is actually not a bad model so
children fall a lot and where is uh when
people were designing robots say oh we
cannot have the robot fall well for
physical robots there a issue but I'll
come to that children fall a lot but it
doesn't hurt them because they have soft
bodies and they have low centers of
gravity so when they fall they just get
up and start working again so she is
Tred to collect data on how often they
fall so in one hour they might have
fallen like 100 times so if you add it
up over the course of how many you know
a child learning to walk it's quite a
bit it may not be in the billions but it
is
certainly uh you know in in the in the
Thousand to million category okay so
that trial and error is part of human
learning okay so I mean that's that's
one observation
but the observation that I like the most
and to me was very influential was this
one so here's this kid who's uh who's uh
walking okay so we are now what are we
looking for we looking for Gates right
either the walk gate or the Run gate now
let's see what actually
happens okay let me repeat okay so this
is uh this notation here stand for S
means side f means front b means back so
this is like what kind of a step the
child has taken
okay
side side front
front back back
right okay where is that periodic gate
going on for you know forever there is
no gate here what there are are so this
is the the slogan most walking bouts
contain omnidirectional not forward
steps so the child is not learning with
like pre-programmed gate from which the
child starts and then is just
fine-tuning the parameters of that there
isn't a gate to begin
with now a very important point to note
here is that this is not necessarily
true in all species so we're talking
here about human babies this may not be
true of a cockroach so it may be that
when a cockroach is Born the Cockroach
does have a gate pre-programmed through
a central through a cpg okay that's
totally possible and because these other
animals have much much smaller brains
and uh and they also don't have the time
to afford to spend in
learning so like there are these
pictures of these mountain goats they're
born and then pretty much they they're
able to walk right uh well not true of
human babies right when is a baby able
to walk there's more like one year old
because we are and there's a distinct
the the people talk about this in
Psychology there different kinds of
species these uh these species where
which have
early where there is a long period of
development where the child is
essentially helpless and relying on the
care of uh parents to take care of them
for this extended period
and then they can afford to have this
huge period of learning and that gives
them
eventually Much More Much much smarter
brains so species which have this long
period of development as opposed to
being pre-programmed and ready to go on
day one or R1 or second one they there
is there's a distinction here and this
is true I mean humans are of course
Prime examples of that right I mean till
the age of 18 you're dependent on your
parents I don't know maybe you're
dependent till 40 whatever but uh the uh
this is also True by the way among birds
so chickens they are not relying on this
period of uh development when uh when
they are uh relying on their parents
they're ready but they have small brains
crows on the other hand are much smarter
and they have a longer period of
development where they're relying on the
parent to take care of them because they
are not able to function fully on their
own so so again this is a topic on which
many papers have been written uh Allison
gnik our colleague in Psychology has
written papers on this theme okay now uh
now I want to come to a concrete
robotics example so because of this we
decided when we built our walking robots
we are not going to pre-program in Gates
so we are just going to pre-program in
general principles like move forward
uh smooth movement minimize energy and
and those principles but there was no
pre-programmed gate and the advantage of
that was that when we train our robots
with different Target speeds so uh a
Target speed of 375 m/ second then this
kind of gate emerged so what you see
here are uh you know right front left
front right rear left rear so the solid
corresp part corresponds to when the
foot is on the
ground and and then this is the gate
which emerges when you give it a higher
Target speed and it turns out that these
different gates are emergent these were
not
pre-programmed and uh uh all that was
necessary was the principle that you
minimize your energy
consumption so I think we got something
cool out of this this result but the
starting point was this observation from
the Child Development literature that
children do not have pre-programmed
Gates they're sort of learning to take
steps so therefore let's do learning all
the way rather than free program in a g
and that gave us actually this very nice
result at end and and then this can be
tied to energy consumption and so so I I
picked this example
which to me or to our research group was
was very cool because of that
philosophical commitment to looking at
Child Development we got a nice result
for
robotics okay next Point uh
multimodality so multimodality just
means different senses like Vision touch
hearing and so on and so
forth and uh so we'll go into this in
detail but this is from houses's work
and here when you want to Sol Sol a hard
uh rotation problem so the task is
rotating an object in the hand it turns
out that for simple tasks you can do it
by just proprioception but when the task
becomes hard like rotating about
different axes then you get value out of
using uh using both vision and touch and
here you see this camera which is
providing Vision information and then
there is a touch information which is
shown in the images on the right so uh
so here is the here are examples of the
task okay so that just each row
corresponds to rotation about different
axes and the generalization across
different but the the the takeaway that
I want you to have because this is just
one task but I believe it's going to be
true in multiple tasks that when the
task becomes more difficult you need
more sensing and in this case you need
vision and touch and the the the the
this figure is the important one which
is uh that the rightmost column
corresponds to the so the the y axis
here is about how successful you are at
the task and in terms of accumulating
rotation reward so the rightmost column
is what you do if you have knowledge of
the ground truth shape and position of
the object which in reality you are not
going to have because you have to get
that from sensing
and the leftmost column is where uh uh
you you just rely on proception and then
in the second and third one correspond
to just having Vision or just having
touch and then the fourth one is having
vision and touch together so vision and
touch together give you as almost the
same performance of having access to
ground tro so this is for a specific
task of rotating an object in the hand
but my belief is that this pattern will
hold good for different tasks if the
task is easy prop perception will be
enough if the task is hard you might
need to have uh Vision or touch or
audition I mean you know and more the
better and it it depends on the
difficulty of the task now certain tasks
which are very popular in robotics is
like pick and place so in my mind pick
and place is an easy task and in fact in
the my previous talk I already said to
you picking up an object does not
require Vision it doesn't require Vision
in a continuous loop to pick up the
object you should use Vision to look at
the object find where it is uh get the
3D location and then you should be able
to release your uh you have your uh
trajectory and you execute it and and
now you need at the end you need touch
to fine tune your finger placement or
whatever but you don't not need need
Vision except for the initial planning
right you do not need it as a continuous
feedback loop you did need it as a
continuous feedback loop in this task
because it's a more subtle
task okay here's another example uh now
this is one which shows how multiple
modalities help you because one modality
can train the other modality so in the
AI and machine learning literature there
has been a lot of discussion
of unsupervised learning or
self-supervised learning or supervised
learning or reinforcement learning and
uh this has gone on for like a decade
and the reason is that most of the the
early or big successes of AI have come
from supervised learning and supervised
learning usually means you have an army
of people somewhere that you pay them
you know $10 an hour and then they're
marking for every object there is a
chair there's a dog there's a cat etc
etc right and then you have this
training set and then you train your
model now this is not how humans learn I
gave you that example of that kid right
the kid the number of examples of zebra
that a kid gets from his or her parents
are very few but the kid has got all
this expertise based on interacting with
the world and acting in the world okay
so this one was the following problem
okay so here we have this robot and what
we are trying to do is to uh calibrate
its Vision
system and we want to do it in a
self-supervised way so uh what is the
advantage of vision again connect back
to the last lecture vision is a distance
sense Vision enables you to know about
some aspect of the environment before
you actually get there so it's it gives
you a lot of safety right right if you
once you get get there you you you you
you could be you could fall into a ditch
Vision tells you in advance if I
continue in that direction I'm going to
fall into a ditch that's a beauty of
vision so a few seconds late earlier
from the safety of a safe position you
know what the consequences are right
that's the advantage of vision okay but
how do we train this Vision system so it
it goes back to the example that that we
had in the first part of this lecture
how how did nema's Vision system know
how many steps to take or the motor
system somehow there must have been some
calibration process I mean throughout
your life you're are
calibrating so that's what we are trying
to model in this experiment so now the
idea is that when the robot is standing
on the stairs then if you look at the
feet of the
robot and uh these are joints uh links
and Joints so the so presumably you know
your own body so therefore you can solve
the forward kinematics problem or
inverse kinematics problem so by working
out the geometry you can actually figure
out that the front foot is 6 in above
the uh where the rear foot is right you
can see how mathematically that could be
worked out just from The Joint angles
which you know from
proception right okay I want to use this
as a training signal for my vision
system because my vision system doesn't
know in advance where something is so
there's my vision system which I want to
calibrate using my proi reception system
so uh so now think of when the robot is
walking and like let's just view this
problem how much higher the height of my
front feet relative to my back
feet which I can calculate from prop
perception so as I'm moving I'm going to
know this this number 6 in 7 in 12 in
whatever right and that's what this
curve is it's going to move up and down
in some
way right you you you you understand how
we can get this
curve okay and now what we imagine is
that we shift this back in time
oh
sorry what happened I wanted to show
this figure is
got oh good okay so I can let's say I
can shift this curve I can take whatever
my propioceptive system discovers and I
can shift this back in time by 2
seconds and then what I can do is I can
tell the vision system to make that
prediction for two seconds in the
future so 2 seconds from now my appropri
setion will know the how much higher my
front foot is over my rear
foot okay I have my image that I
collected now so I have the image
collected at time
and the propri receptive signal at time
T +2 and I can try to take from the
image at time T predict the appropriate
receptive signal at time T
plus2 so this is
self-supervision I didn't need to send
off this image somewhere for people to
label this as a cat or a dog it's all
self-supervised it is from the the the
the robot's own
trajectory and uh that's what we are
showing here so you take the shift
signal from proception and now your
vision data which is some set of pixels
you make those pixels try to predict
what the propri receptive signal would
be 2 seconds from now so now your vision
has become a forward
predictor okay which is what we need
because in Walking the benefit of vision
is forward
prediction okay now uh what we for this
what is important is that initially the
robot have some policy with which it can
walk because there's a chicken and egg
problem so the the thing here is you can
walk even though clumsily when you are
blind so this robot has doesn't have
this
sophisticated uh forward prediction but
it can walk and it collects this data so
it's got proceptive data it's got Vision
data now you train the system
right and and uh this is what we going
to see here so we actually think of it
as days of training so the first day the
robot is not very good in terms of
walking but it's collecting this data of
vision and proception now you use that
to train this forward predictor so the
second day it walks
better and then on the third day it's
really very smooth because now the
vision system has become good at uh
doing this kind of forward prediction
yeah clumsily but
so it's not very effective it at some
step point it just sort of falls down
and so on so we can walk blind right it
just not very well you can have a policy
which can walk blind there's a standard
trick for this which is which you you
can acquire with reinforcement Lear it's
what's called foot tapping so you tap
the foot against the step and if it is
if it encounters a step then you next
time you try slightly higher then you
try slightly higher until finally it
clears the step so that and that it
discovers all yeah so once you have like
Vision model that can predict where like
the joints will be in two seconds now
something what do you do with that
because to me it seems like this you
already have no no so so you need to
have trained a policy which can exploit
that information so we train two
policies in simulation one which is a
blind policy and one which is a cheating
policy which acts as if it has knowledge
of what will be happening 2 seconds in
the future now this policy cannot
actually be run in the real world but it
can be run in the real world once you
have this Vision system which can do
this
prediction and uh I think I don't know
if this video will work
but uh this I think the video is broken
but we did this experiment where we took
the the vision system of the robot and
rotated the camera so this is something
which will totally mess up the
calibration but what happens is that as
it the robot walks it collects collects
data collects data in the right setting
and then it works and this is uh this is
something that psychologists had studied
before it's called the prism adaptation
experiment and it's done like the
following so imagine that I'm so I have
my glasses right and I'm going to reach
some object and I can reach that now
what you do is you put a prism in front
of my eye or let's say one eye shut the
other I put a prism so that all the rays
are deviated by 20 degrees so then when
I try to reach I be I'll be off I'll be
off by 20° and I'll keep trying this and
I'll be very frustrated but sooner or
later I'll figure this out and my system
will become correct what's going on is
this kind of
adaptation okay now you play another
trick on me which is now you remove the
prism and now suddenly you're going to
be off again and then you will recover
so uh you can find videos on this in
YouTube If you look for it it's called
prism adaptation there are versions of
this there's another version of it which
is suppose you wear glasses which are
upside down glasses so they invert the
the image upside down and uh can you
learn to bike in that and the answer is
yes and the person who actually showed
this experiment was a psychologist at
Berkeley his name was Straton and he did
these experiments like 100 years ago and
he mastered the trick of how to bike
with inverting glasses and then of
course once you remove those glasses
then it becomes then you to again
unlearn that behavior so our visual
system and motor systems are always
adapting and this to me is an amazing
capability which would be nice to have
in robotics because then you you are you
become robust to errors you know like
like if one of your mo one of the joints
so like when we are walking we can have
trouble with like sprain an ankle it
doesn't mean that now you're kaput
you're still able to walk with the limp
and and so this ability to constantly
adapt is to me a very uh is is a very
useful thing to have and if you can
figure out uh sort of these adaptation
procedures which are always running
right then uh that would be
great okay incremental let me give you
an example of incremental so this is
when we have a policy which we can train
for uh uh for uh walking then here what
we do is on top of that we learn a
different Behavior which is what's
called Pursuit evasion Behavior so so
this is the pursuit evasion Behavior so
this
dog is chasing this woman okay and she
is so you can think of it as like a fun
hideand-seek game or whatever okay so uh
but notice that she she fools him right
uh him it okay so
uh so and now you could imagine solving
this this by an end to endend training
problem where you try to train for this
task and it will probably not work or it
would take lots and lots of Trials it
turns out that if you do it in a
two-stage way first you train a policy
which can walk but it has given a
Direction so given any direction of
movement and an ability you you should
have ability to translate and rotate
with your train first and on top of that
now you learn the Strategic behavior of
how to uh catch somebody and it turns
out that there are various behaviors
that you need one is that you need to do
this predictive uh thing which is that
you go not to where the person is but
where the person will be right and that
should emerge you shouldn't have to
program that in it should emerge because
you are solving a reinforcement learning
problem and the reward is for catching
the Target and in order to catch the
target the uh the the robot has to do
this prediction other things which
emerge are like seeking Behavior so if
you don't see the Target right now then
you should look around until you see the
target so that also emerges it doesn't
have to be built in so so this is an
example of the value of incrementality
which is you learn some skill then you
learn another skill on top and then you
learn another skill on top and so on
it's very rare the case that we are
learning uh tabularasa we as we are
children we acquire a series of skills
so let me give you examples from
manipulation the the the skill that
children acquire early is that of
reaching so they are when they are in
their tribs they flailing about and they
move their arms so as to so that their
hand can touch something they get
pleasure just from that touch at that
stage their ability to form grasps is
not there they are not able to grasp the
object or manipulate it but they're just
able to get their hand to the right
location then later on they start
forming grasps and the first set of
grasps are these power grasps and then
after that you get Precision grasp and
so on so but there are some skills
learned and then there are other skills
learned on top of that and other skills
learn on top of
that okay but that poses the the
following question question uh how do
you decide what is that sequence of
skills right what is that curriculum and
that to me is a mystery because ideally
I would like not to hand build that in
okay but maybe this is part of what you
uh what you uh what you get from uh your
genetics so my my my theory on this
which may be false is that there only
two things you need from genetics one is
the rewards stru structure and the
second is the curriculum everything else
can be learned but I have no way to
prove this
the okay and then these are okay these
are just more fun examples of uh in
Berkeley this sort of chasing
Behavior okay B physical explore okay
let me give you an example of
this so this is a paper from like okay
long time ago it's learning to poke by
poking okay uh let's give a demo of
this okay so what is the task here this
is not a prehensile task it's a
nonprehensile task it's
essentially that there is some object
you have a photo of the object there's
some camera looking at
it and you're given there is some
initial configuration of this object
object and then there's some desired
final configuration and what you have to
do is to just uh poke the object or you
can do multiple pokes until it reaches
the final configuration it's a fairly
trivial task just push an it's pushing
but pushing from some start
configuration to some desired end
configuration okay so how do you solve
this
problem so the idea here is that
learning to poke by poking meaning that
you're going to do little experiments
like a child does by which you you build
a model of if I apply this force in this
direction then this happens and what
happens may vary depending on the object
and so on and so
forth okay so how does the set up so the
the setup is that we actually want to
have a forward model and an inverse
model actually let me show you the next
slide so what's a forward model so the
forward model is it's given an
image it's given some action okay so the
control action in terms of what for to
apply and uh I mean these go through
some neural network and then it predicts
what will be the end state so if I poke
the object at uh you know 27 comma 31 it
goes by this force it goes to 45 comma
76 something like that right you'll have
a set of observations which you will
then use to train these neural networks
so that's a forward model I mean and
this concept is an important one and
people in Neuroscience have had this
concept for like 30 40 years that we
have a forward model of the consequences
of our actions okay what's an inverse
model inverse model is I have the
initial configuration I have the desired
final configuration tell me what is the
PO to apply I mean this is what you have
to do to solve the to solve the task the
the one in the bottom the forward model
is basically what that Craig slide was
about that we we have these models of
the of the world the inverse model is
what enables you to actually do
something to achieve a
goal and uh and the setup there is
basically that you you have the the
images you run them through some layers
of the neural network and then you
predict the action
and then there is some detail about how
we train these models so we essentially
train the forward and inverse model
together but I mean this detail is not
important what's important here is that
we do not do this in pixel space and
this point is worth noting because there
is a whole industry of people who want
to do video prediction which has existed
for again quite some time and I think a
little bit uh not very successful in my
view and in that that that whole line of
work was often about predicting
pixels and uh okay maybe now you can say
okay something like uh you know like
these generation models are sort of
doing something like that but I
fundamentally don't find that super
interesting to me the uh I want to do
the predictions and there's more
abstracted space this abstracted space
where the object is in some location and
it gets to some other location and uh uh
that's what we are after here and this
is not a general solution this is not
they solving the problem just for poking
but the philosophy which it captures
which is that you have a you you perform
some experiments in the world you use
that to build get data from which you
build a forward model and your
simultaneously building an inverse model
and then uh prediction can be done using
the forward model
If You observe a video you can do
prediction from the forward model if you
are a robot and you need to solve the
task of doing rearrangement then you use
the inverse model
question or a location of the object or
whatever
yeah and and and this is a whole area in
itself but I I believe in More
abstracted Level predictions rather than
pixels
uh but uh let's let's go back to okay
the architecture here is not interesting
I mean it's like just uh the Siamese net
kind of architecture
here uh but but but this was the
important philosophical point be
physical be explore explore collect
trajectories which you can use for uh
for training your
model uh but uh okay going back to my
propaganda point which is how we went
down this path or how pulkit went down
this path was exactly because he was
inspired looking at the Child
Development
literature
okay be social okay this is easy be
social means learn from
others and uh so this is imitation
learning and uh and I think at Berkeley
we've been doing this now for some time
this was I think the earliest paper
which is in collaboration with Sergey
and Peter's group and uh here the idea
was you have this this guy doing
cartwheels we have YouTube videos of
that we use that for training the atlas
robot to do the same sequence and now
you have a dense reward because at every
frame uh it's it's being done in a in a
physics emulator but in every frame you
have a target of what what's a desired
pose and you may not be able to achieve
it because the Dynamics of the atlas
robot and this guy may not be the same
but uh he'll try to do the best it
C and uh and then uh and then but uh it
time okay five minutes that's fine so uh
humanoid
Locomotion uh so we have various bits of
work at berkele which are in the spirit
so we'll we'll talk about this in detail
later but uh uh here uh here's the good
picture which is that to make this
humanoid walk uh Ilia made use of
trajectories which are from humans like
walking in this kind of a video stream
so you can detect the human 3dy the
human get their joint angles transfer
them to the humanoid now you've got a
trajectory and then this is training
data and the training data is used for
sort of this next token
prediction kind of task and it turns out
that you uh doing that enables you to
generalize and learn
faster we'll do this later but okay just
to enjoy this video
so I think now IIA has videos which are
it going up and down speaks so go
that okay okay another example of
learning from others is how we learn to
perform various manipulation tasks so
here let's say there is some you know uh
like there's probably like
clean some cooking operation or cleaning
operation or whatever and the idea is
that we have trajectories of that we
have trajectories from uh YouTube videos
so what we want to do is to lift these
to 3D by lifting the hand to 3D and the
object to 3D and then these become
training data for manipulation skill and
uh we'll again talk about these things
later uh but uh because uh I'm going to
run out of time but the high level uh we
have like a series of lectures on visual
imitation but where it fits into this
child development rubric is this is
being social this is learning from
others and a lot of our learning is like
that so think about when people are
learn to be a become a bike mechanic I
mean they don't learn to be a bike
mechanic by just reading books or by
just blind experimentation on they they
go work in a bike shop and then the a
senior bike specialist who who does
something who shows the operations now I
think that that example actually
illustrates a lot because uh when you go
and become an apprentice mechanic you're
actually not starting from zero you have
a whole bunch of manipulation skills
already which you acquired as a child
growing up doing various experiments
playing with toys and so on and then
at the age of 18 you go and become an
apprenticeship in a bike shop and you
can you can uh you can learn very fast
so uh I think I got I'll skip this this
is about hand reconstruction this is
about object reconstruction again we'll
do these things in G detail later but
uh I'll end here thanks